Daniel Rossano

Edmonds, WA - 860.558.0400 - daniel.rossano10@gmail.com - https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-rossano-6a192228/

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am a passionate engineer seeking to leverage my strong analytical experience, leadership skills and efficiency improvement ideas to increase company profitability. I have 11+ years of broad analytical experience including Python programming, data analytics, data engineering, process improvements, machine learning/AI and predictive forecasting.

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Python, AWS, SQL, Azure, Snowflake, MongoDB, Data Mining, Web Scraping, React JS, Terraform, Cosmos, Apache Airflow, Databricks, Pyspark, R, Hive, Presto, Kafka, Postgres SQL, Photoshop/website front-end design, SAP, Tableau, Veeva, Oracle, Jupyter Notebook, Big Data analysis, Data Warehousing, Data Modelling, Process improvements, Machine learning, Flask, Django, Fast API, Artificial Intelligence, A/B testing, Advanced MS Office Suite, Lean/six-sigma, Networker and team leader.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Senior Data Engineer – September 2022 – Current Symetra – Bellevue, WA

• Build AWS CloudFormation YAML pipelines.

Data Engineer – September 2022 – March 2023

United Health Care – Redmond, WA

- Involved in designing and deploying a multitude of applications utilizing almost all of the AWS stack including EC2, Route53, S3, RDS, Dynamo DB, Athena, Lambda, Glue, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance and auto scaling in AWS cloud formation/Terraform.
- Build AWS automated data pipelines utilizing AWS S3, Lambda, Glue and Athena to transfer on-prem data into the cloud for more efficient data processing.
- Developed a single page application with Fast API for displaying JSON data using React JS.
- Automate provisioning and repetitive tasks using Terraform and Python.
- Using software engineering best practices using Bitbucket and Github.
- Provisioning Spark clusters to build the On-Demand Data warehouse and provide the data for our Data Science team.
- Developed an on-prem end-to-end pipeline solution utilizing Pythons' multithreading and SQLAlchemy packages. The pipeline solution saved over 4 day's worth of data processing time.

Senior Commercial Data Analyst – November 2020 – September 2022

Seagen - Bothell, WA

- Built and deployed a python script that will replace the use for our department's Dell Boomi system. The script is currently on track for saving Seagen over 1,000+ hours in labor for the year of 2022.
- Built out the data and reporting infrastructure from the ground up using Power BI and SQL to provide real-time insights into the product, marketing channels and business KPIs.
- Built Power Automate workflows to solve daily repeatable tasks, saving the company and my team hours of time.
- Performed statistical analysis on sales territory performance using supervised learning methods such as regression, classification, and decision trees using Python's Scikit-learn.
- Created a Python script that automatically compares two separate data sources and automatically notifies users if any errors are found via email.
- Built an automated email notification program that notifies sales team members of product status in their territory using Python and SQL. This process replaces the sales team from checking a power BI report manually.
- Worked with Petabyte sized data using Spark and Apache Hadoop to identify gaps and inconsistencies, provided data insights, and provided product solutions.
- Built and implemented Apache Airflow DAGs to streamline Commercial workflows. Helped eliminate unnecessary processes and helped reconfigure our groups ETL pipeline layout saving over 30 minutes a week.
- Analyzed sales members' data using Power BI/SQL and Snowflake while navigating multiple data sources.
- Created and implemented test plans to support Seagen's Commercial sales team's Power BI database.

The Boeing Company – Everett, WA

- Performed sophisticated ad-hoc or ongoing custom analyses against factory efficiency to support business stakeholders and created visual displays to present data using Tableau.
- Designed and populated specific tables, databases for collection, tracking and reporting of data.
- Managed the planning and development of design and procedures for metrics reports.
- Investigated and conducted studies on the forecasts, demand, and capital of products.
- Applied Lean processes to achieve improvements to drive quality and managing the cost, decreasing it 10% in one year.
- Networked with multiple departments to build relationships among the peers.
- Worked with cross-functional groups to expedite parts to the factory that resulted in improvement of our timeframe and saved \$100,000 in expenses.

Project Manager - October 2017 – May 2018

Information Science & Service (ISS) - New Hudson, MI

- Led a Standard Work Instructions Project.
- Developed a SharePoint site to house the Standard Work Instructions, making them accessible globally, and adding version control.
- Developed metrics to track SharePoint utilization.
- Identified existing workflows and wrote Standard Work Instructions for the newly optimized workflows and presented data using Power BI.
- Proposed solutions to improve system efficiencies and reduce total expenses.

Data Analyst - September 2014 - September 2016

QuEST Global Engineering – Windsor Locks UTAS, CT

- Managed a team of four and oversaw component removal data collection and performed analysis.
- Presented data and conclusions to team to improve strategies and operations.
- Optimized data collection procedures and generated reports on a weekly, monthly, and quarterly basis.
- Identified existing workflows, mapped, and tracked.

Senior Engineer - October 2013 - September 2014

- Improved data mining processes, resulting in a 15% decrease in time needed to infer insights from customer data used to develop design change strategies.
- Saved QuEST over \$90,000 in process improvements in 2014.
- Optimized workflows to enhance productivity/efficiency/speed.
- Developed metrics to track project speed through engineering start-of-work to handoff.
- Streamlined and managed supplier's inventory and processes and implemented cost savings improvements resulting in \$10,000 dollars saved. .

Project Engineer - March 2012 – October 2013

- Constructed technical documents for mechanical and electrical systems on the 787-8 Boeing Dreamliner.
- Facilitated team meetings, worked with engineers to establish a plan of schedule, helped engineers write technical documents, tracked group progress until project completion.
- Managed a hardware-tracking Excel database, cross-referenced multiple software programs, and collaborated with engineers to ensure schedule and deadlines were met.

RECOGNITION & AWARDS

- Awarded Team impact award for my Python automation improvements 2022
- Received over \$1,000 dollars in awards for creation of process improvement tools, 2014-15
- QuEST, Employee of the Month, December 2012

EDUCATION

Python programming certification – University of California, Irvine – March 2022 - **PCEP -** Python for Data Science, Web and Core Programming

- Schema design and high-dimensional data modeling using machine learning techniques.
- Projects included multiclass classification using machine learning methods, data wrangling and compiling hundreds of CSV files using Python, and logistic regression model creation and interpretation.

University of Connecticut – Storrs, CT – December 2010 - BA, Sociology focused in Social Statistics

Manchester Community College – Manchester, CT – May 2009 AA in Liberal Arts & Science focus in Business Studies